《旺达幻视》前情提要
Previously on WandaVision...
你已经进入边界两次了  莫妮卡
You've gone through the boundary twice already, Monica.
里面的能量
The energy inside has
在分子层面上两次改写了你的细胞
re-written your cells on a molecular level twice.
我知道旺达的感受  不帮到她我不罢休
I know what Wanda's feeling and I won't stop until I help her.
我想联系西景镇外界
It is my intention to reach those outside of Westview
弄清我们现在的状况
and make sense of our situation.
帮帮里面的人
The people need help.
妈妈  妈妈
Mom! Mom!
什么  怎么了  比利
What? What is it, Billy?
我听见了爸爸的声音  他出事了
I hear Dad. He's in trouble.
你那死人丈夫又不会死第二回
It's not like your dead husband can die twice.
马克西莫夫本就不可能跟我们谈判
Maximoff was never gonna negotiate with us.
我们打不过她
We can't outgun her.
显然  跟她对立只让事情更糟了
And clearly antagonizing her is only making things worse.
如果旺达是问题所在  那解铃还须系铃人
If Wanda is the problem, she has to be our solution.
该死
Oh, fudge!
漫威
影业
我们都经历过  是吧
Look, we've all been there, right?
被恐惧和愤怒控制
Letting our fear and anger get the best of us,
有意扩展了
intentionally expanding
我们创造了虚构世界的范围
the borders of the false world we created.
让开  让开
Move it! Move it!
妈妈  你会很快下来吗
Mom, are you coming down soon?
妈妈  我们的电游在发疯
Mom, our game is freaking out.
她在睡觉吗
Is she asleep?
妈妈没在睡觉
Mommy's not sleeping, honey.
她在休息眼睛
She's just resting her eyes.
妈妈  我的脑袋感觉好怪
Mom, my head feels weird.
好吵
It's, like, really noisy.
我不喜欢
I don't like it.
休息眼睛
Resting her eyes.
为了惩罚我鲁莽的一晚
As punishment for my reckless evening,
我打算进行隔离形式的家里蹲
I plan on taking a quarantine-style staycation.
一整天
A whole day...
就我自己
just to myself.
这能让我知道错
That'll show me.
我先拿的
I got to it first!
你总是先拿
You always get to it first!
杏仁奶
西景乳业  维D牛奶  纯天然
失踪
西景乳业
嗯  我也不知道那怎么回事
Yeah, I'm not sure what that's about.
可能是只是周一的问题
It's probably just a case of the Mondays.
是吧
Am I right?
你好
我叫
旺达街
旺达
母带[主人]
抱歉  我们
旺达
知道你在做什么吗
旺达薯条牛排
旺达
我爱
幻视
旺达
第七集
旺达・马克西莫夫制作
天剑局临时驻点
我们真幸运  她最终住手了
Lucky for us, she pumped the brakes.
是啊  我可真幸运
Yeah. I feel very lucky.
放送信号怎么样了
What's happening with the broadcast?
毫无动静  信号没了
Dead air. The signal's gone.
务必确保团队什么都不缺
Make sure the team has everything they need.
我们今天发射
We launch today.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
你是新小丑吗
You're the new clown?
至少你已经化好妆了
At least you're already in makeup.
你跟逃脱大师的彩排迟到了
You're late for rehearsal with the escape artist.
来吧
Come on.
嗯  老实说  我不怎么擅长这活儿
Yeah, I'm not great at this gig, I gotta be honest.
跟我的技能不怎么相称
It doesn't really speak to my skill set.
我本想做胡子女
I put in for the bearded lady,
但这种雪花石膏的肤色骗不了任何人
but this alabaster complexion wasn't fooling anyone.
有事吗  变态
Can I help you, creeper?
你不记得我们昨晚的事了吗
You don't remember me from last night?
我们目光相对过  有种不言的理解
We locked eyes. There was a unspoken understanding.
少他妈来了吧
Um, hard pass.
不  等等  等等
No, wait. Wait up.
你们看到爸爸了吗
Have you seen your dad?
没
Um, no.
你要去找他吗
Do you wanna go look for him?
如果他不想待在这里
Well, if he doesn't wanna be here,
我也没办法
there's nothing I can do about it.
五日天气预报
周一到周五晴天  周日可能多云
妈妈  昨晚
Hey, Mom, last night,
皮舅舅说什么要再杀爸爸一次
Uncle P said that thing about re-killing Dad?
别相信那男人说的任何话  他不是你们的舅舅
Don't believe anything that man said. He is not your uncle.
那他是谁
Who is he?
是这样的  孩子们
Here's the thing, boys.
我是你们妈妈
I'm your mom.
因此
And as such,
你们会指望我什么都知道  是吧
you were counting on me to have all the answers, right?
但我不是的
Well, I don't.
我...
I have...
什么都不知道
no answers.
一点都不
Zip. Zero. Zilch.
完全不
Nada. Niente.
我开始认为
I'm starting to believe
一切都是
that everything is...
无意义的
meaningless.
你们当然可以自己得出结论
You're welcome to draw your own conclusions, of course,
但我现在是这样想的
but that's just where I'm at.
好吧  或许我那是有点黑暗了
Okay. So maybe I went a little too dark there,
但他们会没事的
but they'll be fine.
幻视可是振金的  他们继承了坚强的外壳
Vision is made of vibranium. They literally inherited tough skin.
来吧
Come on.
艾格妮丝  进来吧
Hi, Agnes. Come on in.
我该起来  但我不想
I'd get up, but I just don't want to.
我觉得我出现得非常及时
But I think I got there in the nick of time
不然她可能差点就要自己剪刘海了
'cause she was one split end away from cutting her own bangs.
孩子们  给你妈妈一点私人时间吧
Hey, boys, why don't we give your mom some me time?
艾格尼丝  你确定吗
Agnes, are you sure?
绝对确定
Oh, abso-positively.
-来  走吧  -我们一定要走吗  妈妈
- Come on, let's go, guys. - Do we have to, Mom?
得有人留在这里照顾你啊
Someone needs to be here to take care of you.
孩子们  我没事的  和艾格尼丝去吧
Boys, I'll be fine. Just go with Agnes.
我保证我不会咬人
I promise I won't bite.
我其实以前咬过一个孩子
I actually did bite a kid once.
艾格尼丝  你简直是我的救星
Agnes, you are a life-saver.
-有什么我能帮你做的吗  -你知道吗
- Is there anything I can do for you? - You know what?
我背上看不见得地方好像是长了一个痦子
I do have a suspicious mole on my back that I just can't see.
距离感  我明白
Boundaries. I get it.
不用多说
Say no more.
好了  先生们  赶紧走吧
All right, gentlemen, let's keep it moving.
你们知道吗  要是你们俩能帮我看一眼
You know what? If one of you two could take a quick look,
那真是太感激了  就在我的...
I'd appreciate it. It's right here above my...
...在球门外展开了完美得进攻
...delivering flawless offensive plays right out of the gate.
最后的进球是精彩...
The final goal scored with a remark...
我没事  我没事  我没事
I'm fine. I'm fine. I'm fine. I'm fine.
我没事
I'm fine.
天剑局
达西穿过了最后一道防火墙
Darcy made it through that last firewall, all right.
她有什么发现
Oh, what'd she find?
研发报告  都是同一个项目的
R and D reports. All on the same project.
达西・刘易斯
你好  吉米  我突破了防火墙
有很多关于同一个项目的研究报告  代号幻光
我发现了幻视身体的构造图  海沃德没有解构幻视
他是想要利用天剑局的资源让他复活  他尝试了很多次
但是都没有用  直到旺达偷走了幻视的尸体
这是他给幻视办公室发的假公报
达西
代号  幻光
Code name, Cataract.
海沃德没有解构幻视
Hayward wasn't decommissioning Vision.
他想要复活幻视  但是一直没有成功  直到...
He was trying to bring him back online. Nothing worked until...
旺达偷走了幻视的尸体
Wanda stole Vision's body.
所以他如此执着于在六边域里找到幻视
That's why he was so focused on tracking Vision inside the Hex.
海沃德要拿回他的有意识武器
Hayward wants his sentient weapon back.
这件事得找人告诉旺达
Someone has to tell Wanda.
看  他们在那里
Look. There they are.
-古德纳少校  -兰博上尉
- Major Goodner. - Captain Rambeau.
这是吴探员
This is Agent Woo.
认识你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
非常感谢你的到来
Thank you so much for coming.
我的母亲会很感谢你的忠心
My mother would appreciate your loyalty.
我们不仅只听命于她  上尉
She's not the only one we're loyal to, Captain.
让我带你去看看我们带来了什么
Let me show you what we brought you.
符合你的期待规模吗
Did we get your specs right?
太完美了
She's perfect.
天剑局
喂  不好意思  你之前想帮我的
Hello? Excuse me. Uh, you tried to help me.
那可不一定  我是出了名的自私自利
Doubtful. I'm notoriously self-involved.
不不不  拜托  听我说
No, no, no. Please. Just hear me out.
好吧  我相信你是隶属于
All right. I believe that you were part of a team
一个专门监管超自然现象的团队  现在...
monitoring a supernatural anomaly. And now...
你也进来了
Well, you're in it.
好吧  我愿意和你约会  但我要点龙虾
Fine. I'll go out with you, but I'm ordering the lobster.
不  看  那个演哑剧的  他的盘子太重了
Oh, no. Look, that mime... His tray is getting too heavy.
你的腰不好
Oh, your bad back!
哇哦  好吧
Whoa! Okay. Ooh.
-醒了吗  -嗯
- Awake? - Ooh, uh, yeah.
没事吧
All right?
你好啊  我自己
Oh, hello, self.
我内心是有点偷偷想客串这部戏
You know, part of me secretly wanted a guest spot on the show,
但说真的  那糟糕透了
but seriously, that sucked.
你叫什么名字  你的真名
Look, uh, what is your name? Your real name?
达西・刘易斯
Darcy Lewis.
达西・刘易斯博士
Dr. Darcy Lewis.
我截获了一封关于你的研究的信
I intercepted a communication regarding your work.
狮子刚下场  该你们上了
Hey, the lions just got off stage. You're up.
刘易斯博士  我有好多问题
Dr. Lewis, I have questions.
我有答案
I have answers.
我们要不要开这车上路
Ooh, should we take this convo on the road?
-太好了  -该你俩上场了
- Excellent. - You two are up.
不行  真抱歉  博士和我早就约好了
No, I'm so sorry. Doctor and I have a prior engagement.
她哪也不许去
She's not goin' anywhere.
不  我的鼻子
Oh, no! My nose!
-抱歉  -快走
- Sorry. - Come on.
-借过  -你俩要去哪
- Oh. Excuse me. - Where do you think you're going?
给我回来
Get back here!
去你家吗
To your house, I assume?
刘易斯博士  我想问  我的孩子们安全吗
Dr. Lewis, my questions, are my children safe?
我不知道
That I don't know.
那个冒牌货皮特是谁
Who is that imposter, Pietro?
问倒我了
Beats me.
-我们走吧  -太好了
- Let's roll. - Great.
-给我出来  -抱歉  听不清你说什么
- Get out of there. - Sorry. Can't hear you.
-什么  -快开车啊
- What? - Drive!
实在对不起  经纪人把我们的时间约重了
I'm so sorry. We were double-booked by the agents.
你们必须上场
You got to be on stage.
-踩油门啊  达西  -你们在干什么
- Step on it, Darcy! - What are you doing?
我听不见你说什么
No, I can't hear you.
你们给我回来  我需要你们
You get back here! I need you!
我不明白这是怎么回事
I don't understand what's happening.
为什么...
Why it's...
为什么一切都崩溃了  为什么...
Why it's all falling apart and why...
我没办法解决
I can't fix it.
是不是因为你罪有应得
Do you think maybe this is what you deserve?
什么
What?
你不该说话的
You're not supposed to talk.
感觉抑郁
Feeling depressed?
觉得世界没了自己也能继续
Like the world goes on without you?
只想独处吗
Do you just want to be left alone?
向您的医生咨询下"链结"
Ask your doctor about Nexus.
链结
一种独特的抗抑郁药物
A unique anti-depressant
能将您锚定回现实中
that works to anchor you back to your reality.
链结
或者您选择的现实
Or the reality of your choice.
链结
副作用包括感觉到自己的感受
Side effects include feeling your feelings,
面对真相  抓住命运
confronting your truth, seizing your destiny,
而且很可能导致抑郁加深
and possibly, more depression.
除非医生允许您继续生活
You should not take Nexus
否则请勿使用"链结"
unless your doctor has cleared you to move on with your life.
链结
"链结"  因为世界并不是围着您转的
Nexus, because the world doesn't revolve around you.
也可能是呢
Or does it?
萨米
Hey, Sammy.
有人渴了吗
Okay, who's thirsty?
这有饮料
Some bevs.
你在想什么呢
Penny for your thoughts.
我喜欢这里
I like it here.
那很好啊
Oh, good.
是因为挠挠先生会耐心听你倾诉吗
Is it because Se?or Scratchy is such a good listener?
不是
No.
是因为这里很安静
It's because it's quiet.
你很安静  艾格尼丝
You're quiet, Agnes.
你的内心
On the inside.
你觉得我们妈妈没事吗
Do you think our mom is okay?
当然没事了
Oh, for sure!
你们不用担心你们妈妈
Oh, you don't have to worry about your mom.
她无所不能  是超人妈妈
Your mom can do anything. She's supermom.
拉夫说我喜欢粉饰太平
Ralph says I sugarcoat things.
但你试试告诉一个十岁孩子
But you try telling a 10-year-old
他妈妈逼疯了
that his mother is cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs.
最后检查
Final checks.
一切准备就绪  上尉
We're all set, Captain.
谢谢
Thank you.
达西不在这里  没法给你认可
Darcy's not here to give her stamp of approval.
我知道
I know.
她在里面  我会进去救她出来
She's in there and I'm gonna go get her out.
这是我们的最后一搏  吉米
It's our last shot, Jimmy.
祝成功  上尉
Godspeed, Captain.
你对这玩意有多大信心
How much faith you have in this thing?
这是我们防御力最强的太空车
It's our most heavily-armored space rover.
她能直接开进去  毫发不伤
She's gonna sail right through. Unharmed.
检查上尉的通讯设备
Capcom, check.
没问题
Good, check.
听你的指令  上尉
On your order, Captain.
出发
Moving out.
接触倒计时  五  四  三
Contact in five, four, three...
二  一
two, one.
不是说能直接开进去吗
What happened to sailing right through?
密度正和她匹配
The density is matching her.
我快成功了  屏障会被冲破
I'm close. It's gonna give!
结构完整性在降低
The structural integrity is failing.
正在瓦解
It's disintegrating.
不  是正在重写
No, it's being rewritten.
莫妮卡  快下车
Monica, get out of there!
听到吗  莫妮卡
Do you copy, Monica?
莫妮卡  快下车
Monica! Get out of there!
莫妮卡
Monica!
快派救伤直升机
Get a medevac, now!
当心
Watch out!
不  不要
No. No.
我能穿过去
I can get through.
莫妮卡  不
Monica! No!
不  我不能  我不能丢下莫妮卡
No, I can't. I can't leave Monica.
妈妈  没事
Mommy, it's okay.
我可以去外婆外公家住
I can stay with Grandma and Pop-Pop.
我不能去  宝贝  太危险了
There's no way I'm going, baby. It's too dangerous.
妈妈  或许我可以飞上天  和你中途相会
Mom, maybe I could fly up and meet you halfway?
那你得学会像卡罗尔阿姨那样发光
Only if you learn to glow like your Aunt Carol.
你是我认识的最强大的人
And you were the most powerful person I knew.
你妈妈死了  亲爱的
Your mom, she died, honey.
她激励了我们
She was truly an inspiration.
-很遗憾  -不
- Sorry. - No!
你妈妈很幸运
Your mom's lucky.
天上发孩子时  给了她最坚强的一个
When they were handing out kids, they gave her the toughest one.
所以旺达杀了我吗
So, Wanda killed me?
是的  但没那么简单  是你叫她这么做的
Yes, but it's not that simple. You asked her to do it.
我为什么要那么做
Why would I have done that?
拯救全宇宙
To save the universe.
一半的宇宙
Well, half of it.
有效果吗
Did it work?
有啊
It did.
但是反派逆转了时间  亲自杀了你
Until the bad guy rewound time and killed you himself.
虽然中间还有其他小插曲
There are a few extra steps,
但是长话短说
but to set up the context...
我回到过去  又死了一次
I came back and died again.
还让她亲眼看着你死去
And she had to watch.
不是吧  又是红灯
Oh, man, another red light?
在这么偏僻的地方设置红绿灯没必要吧
It's kinda overkill out in the sticks here,
你觉得呢
don't you think?
是啊
Yes.
我觉得  是旺达创造了这些障碍
I believe... I think that Wanda is creating
不让我回家
these impediments to stop me returning home.
再说  西景也没下过雨吧
Also, it never rains in Westview, right?
我很不开心
I'm not amused.
前方
施工
行吧  你们慢慢干吧
Yeah, great. Just take your time, fellas.
如果我理解正确的话
So if I understand correctly,
我最初是一个名叫贾维斯的人工智能
my original code dates back to an AI called Jarvis?
但是我的身体
But my corporeal form
是奥创企图灭绝人类计划的产物
was born of Ultron's plan for global genocide?
完全正确
Correct-o.
那我现在是什么
What am I now?
老实说  我是研究理工科的
Honestly, I'm a STEM type of lady,
所以我觉得她打开了你脑袋里的开关
so I thought she just flipped a switch on your head
让你起死回生
and brought you back to life,
但是我不明白你为什么不能离开六边域
but what I don't get is why you can't leave the Hex.
但是我知道的是
What I do know is I've
上周我一直在看《旺达幻视》
been watching WandaVision for the past week.
你们俩之间的爱意是真的
And the love you two have is real.
你们是天生一对
You belong together.
旺达  旺达
Wanda? Wanda!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
-旺达  -你是怎么进来的
- Wanda... - How did you get in here?
听我说  一切都是为了幻视
Listen to me. This whole thing is about Vision.
-离开我家  -海沃德想让他...
- Get out of my house. - Hayward was trying to bring him...
别跟我说这些  我根本不想听
Don't talk to me about that. I don't wanna hear about it.
无人机  导弹  皮特
The drones, the missiles. Pietro?
不  等等  皮特不是我们安排的
No, wait, Pietro, no, no, no, that wasn't us.
你们只会说谎
All you do is lie!
我说过的只有你让我说的谎言
The only lies I've told are the ones you put in my mouth.
注意你的言辞
Careful what you say to me.
来啊
Do it, then.
把我扔出去
Take me out.
你看  这就是你和海沃德不一样的地方
See, see? That's where you and Hayward differ.
他为了达到目的
He's gonna burn Westview to the ground
不惜把西景镇烧成灰烬
just to get what he wants.
不要让他把你变成凶手
Don't let him make you the villain.
或许我就是凶手
Maybe I already am.
我不怕你  旺达
I'm not afraid of you, Wanda.
我也失去了我最亲近的人
I lost the person closest to me, too.
我可以想象的最糟糕的事情
The worst thing I can think of
已经发生了
has already happened to me
我无力改变  无法挽回
and I can't change it. I can't undo it.
我不能再隐瞒这种痛苦了
I can't control this pain anymore.
我也不想隐瞒了  因为这就是我的真相
And I don't think I want to, because it's my truth.
旺达  你要
Wanda, you have to...
女士  你好像有点得寸进尺了
Young lady, I think you overstayed your welcome.
可怜的旺达已经经历够多了
Poor Wanda's been through enough.
这跟你没关系  旺达
This doesn't concern you. Wanda...
离开吧
Run along, dear.
-旺达  你必须解开这里  -绝不
- Wanda, you have to take it down. - No.
-别逼我伤害你  -好了
- Don't make me hurt you. - All right.
好了  咱们收工吧
Okay, let's wrap it up.
终于结束了
Yes, finally.
停
拜托了
Oh, come on!
孩子们  快跟上
Come on, kids.
孩子们  然后呢  再来一群小狗吗
Kids? What's next, puppies?
我完全想象不到
I had no idea how much
旺达来西景之前到底忍受了多少痛苦
Wanda had endured before coming to Westview,
我想应该说我们都忍受了很多
how much we both had, I guess.
虽然我不记得了
Though I can't remember it.
对我来说  就像发生在别人身上的事一样
For me, it feels like it happened to someone else, you know?
但是对她来说
But for her...
这就是几周前的事
It's mere weeks ago.
我在干什么呢  坐着和你谈心  我明明应该
What am I doing here, sitting, talking to you when I should...
这真是  这太可笑了  我得去找我妻子了
This is... This is absurd. I need to get to my wife.
那我就去那里和你汇合是吧
So I'll just meet you there, then?
过来
Oh, here.
亲爱的  要不要喝杯茶
Would you like a cup of tea, hon?
-好的  谢谢你  艾格尼丝  -没问题
- Sure. Thank you, Agnes. - Okay.
坐吧  我去泡茶  马上回来
Sit down. Be right back with that.
跳呀  跳呀  跳呀
Jump! Jump! Jump!
跳起来  跳呀  跳呀  跳呀
Jumpy, jump, jump, jump, jump
Jumpy, jump, jump, jump, jump, jump
跳起来  跳呀  跳呀  跳呀
Jumpy, jump, jump, jump, jump
Jumpy, jump, jump, jump, jump, jump
我的孩子们在哪儿
Where are the twins?
他们可能就在地下室里玩呢
Oh, they're probably just playing in the basement.
孩子们
Boys?
汤米
Tommy?
比利
Billy?
旺达呀旺达
Wanda, Wanda.
你不会以为镇上就你一个人会法术吧
You didn't think you were the only magical girl in town, did you?
我叫阿加莎・哈克尼斯
The name's Agatha Harkness.
终于和你正式见面了  亲爱的
Lovely to finally meet you, dear.
? 是谁一直在背后搞鬼 ?
? Who's been messing up everything ?
? 一直都是阿加莎 ?
? It's been Agatha all along ?
一直
都是
阿加莎
? 是谁一直在幕后操控一切 ?
? Who's been pulling every evil string ?
? 一直都是阿加莎 ?
? It's been Agatha all along ?
领衔主演
阿加莎・哈克尼斯
? 她阴险又狡猾 ?
? She's insidious ?
? 她是如此奸诈狡猾  而你根本无法察觉 ?
? So perfidious that you haven't even noticed ?
? -而且可惜的是  -可惜的是 ?
? - And the pity is - The pity is ?
? 可惜可惜  太可惜 ?
? Pity, pity, pity, pity ?
? 一切为时已晚  不能回头 ?
? It's too late to fix anything ?
? 大错都已铸成 ?
? Now that everything has gone wrong ?
阿加莎
? 多亏了阿加莎 ?
? Thanks to Agatha ?
? 调皮的阿加莎 ?
? Naughty Agatha ?
? 一直都是阿加莎 ?
? It's been Agatha all along ?
而且是我杀了火花
And I killed Sparky, too.
请稍后
别走开  后面还有
你可真是爱管闲事
Snooper's gonna snoop.